burningshed.com 2018-11-16

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy explains what personal information Burning Shed Ltd collects about you and how it is used by us. 

Where we stand on privacy 

Burning Shed Ltd recognises that your personal information is sensitive and private and will therefore always treat it with respect and confidentiality. 

It is to the benefit of our customers and ourselves that we manage your information responsibly and with transparency. 

Under data protection regulations, you have the right to have your personal information removed at any time from Burning Shed Ltd or indeed, any other company. We make this option clear and simple to achieve for all of our customers. 

Who we are 

Burning Shed Ltd provides services and sells products to its customers. To enable us to deliver on our services, we collect personal information about our customers and how they interact with us. How data we collect about you can be used is based on the consent that you provide. 

We always keep your personal information safe and secure and take a proactive approach to being compliant with government regulations about data protection. 

What information do we collect about you? 

All of the information we collect is used to help us identify you. This is only used for delivering products to you, keeping in contact with you about our products and for dealing with any enquiries you may have about our services. 

Personal information we collect includes: 

Full name  
Postal address for billing and shipping Email address  
Telephone number  
IP address  
PayPal address 

We do not collect or store credit or debit card details.

We also collect data on your purchase history which helps us understand more about what you like and what products are popular more generally. 

Purchase history information we collect includes:

Products you have bought  
Date and times of purchases you make 

When do we collect information about you? 

We collect information about you at any of the following points: 

If you register for an online account  
If you place an order for products or services If you subscribe to one of our newsletters 

If you use our website (via cookies) 

What are cookies? 

Cookies are text files placed on your computer when you interact with our online service, these files contain data needed to use our website (sessions, language, currency and display options). 

These cookies are anonymous and do not contain or associate your name/email address or any sensitive data to a specific behaviour. 

Further information on cookies is available from [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: [https:// www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

Sometimes we - or some of our suppliers - use Facebook Pixel to check how well specific Facebook adverts are working. More information is available here: [https://www.facebook.com/ business/help/742478679120153](https://www.facebook.com/%20business/help/742478679120153)

Twitter might also store cookies when displaying feeds on our pages, more information is available here: <https://dev.twitter.com/web/overview/privacy>

How to remove cookies 

It is possible to block cookies from websites you visit by setting your internet browser to not accept them or to remove them entirely. The websites below provide instructions on how to do this. 

(a)  <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome); 

(b)  <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) [https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete- manage-cookies](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-%20manage-cookies) (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge). 

Please be advised that as a result of removing or not accepting cookies, our website might not work properly. 

How will we use the information about you? 

The information we collect about you is used in a number of ways, all of which are either legally required to fulfil our services to you or because you have given us permission to do so.

We collect information about you to process your order, manage your online account and manage your newsletter subscription(s). We also use it to be able to show your order history and so that you can access any downloads. 

Who we share your information with 

We never sell or give your information to any other organisation. 

However, we need the help of certain providers to manage our services to you. 

Financial transactions relating to Burning Shed are handled by our payment services providers, [WorldPay, Paypal and Barclays Bank]. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding your payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers' privacy policies and practices at

[https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full https://www.barclays.co.uk/important-information/privacy-policy/ ](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full%20https://www.barclays.co.uk/important-information/privacy-policy/)

We may disclose some of your personal data to one or more selected suppliers of goods and services for the purpose of delivering your order. For example, Royal Mail and other courier companies may need your telephone number and email address to complete certain deliveries. Each of these companies will act as a data controller in relation to the data we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data. 

We use different courier companies to deliver to different countries. These include your local postal service, ParcelForce, Fed-Ex and DPD. 

We also send you emails and host our website through external organisations. As such, Burning Shed Ltd will store and use your information through these external companies or other organisations. The providers we work with only store your personal information for the purposes we stipulate and are strictly prohibited from accessing or using your data for any other reason. 

The hosting facilities for our website, downloads and email services are situated in the United States. All of these third-party data processors are GDPR compliant. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the United States of America. Transfers to the USA will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, information about which you can obtain from <https://www.privacytrust.com/privacyshield/gdpr-vs-privacy-shield.html>

All of this helps us to deliver an efficient service for you as a customer. 

Our communication with you 

Whether you are new to Burning Shed or you have shopped with us before, we would like to tell you about our products and services which we are updating all the time. We like to keep you informed if you give us your consent to do so. However, if you have asked to receive this information in the past and you no longer wish to, you can opt out whenever you want to. 

You have the right at any time to stop us from sending you newsletters. If you no longer wish to subscribe for any reason, you can change your subscription preferences within your account or contact us at [support@burningshed.com](mailto:support@burningshed.com) and we will do it for you. 

Access to your information 

You have the right to request a free copy of the information that we hold about you at any time. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email [support@burningshed.com](mailto:support@burningshed.com) or write to us at Burning Shed Ltd, Unit B, Yarefield Park, Old Hall Road, Norwich NR4 6FF, United Kingdom. 

Before we process this request will we need proof of identification to ensure the data is matched correctly and is safe to be despatched to you. 

Removal of your information 

You have the right to request that your personal information be removed from our systems. The only instance in which certain information is necessary for us to still have in this case is to complete a legal obligation, such as fulfilment of an order.

You can request for your details to be removed by contacting [support@burningshed.com](mailto:support@burningshed.com) or by clicking on ‘Delete account (inc. downloads, orders, newsletters)’ in My Account if you are logged in.

We may ask for proof of identification before we process any deletion requests. 

How long do we keep your personal information? 

Burning Shed Ltd keeps personal information for as long as you hold an account with us unless you ask us to delete it. 

We also store data from the previous version of our website that existed prior to May 2017. We keep this data only for providing information about products you have bought in the past and dates and times of purchases you made. 

We also retain some personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Other websites 

Our website may occasionally contain links to other websites. This Privacy Policy only applies to our website. 

If you wish to know how your personal information is used on another website visited via Burning Shed, you will need to refer to their own Privacy Policy. 

Changes to our Privacy Policy 

We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review and we will place any updates on our website at <https://burningshed.com/privacy_policy>

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 11/05/2018 

How to contact us 

This website is owned and operated by Burning Shed Ltd. We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 5740335, and our registered office is at UNIT B, YAREFIELD PARK, OLD HALL ROAD, NORWICH, NR4 6FF, UK. Our VAT number is (GB)813582924 

Please contact us if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or information that we hold about you.

By email – [support@burningshed.com](mailto:support@burningshed.com)  
Or write to Burning Shed Ltd, Unit B, Yarefield Park, Old Hall Road, Norwich NR4 6FF, United Kingdom. 

Supervisory authority 

In the unfortunate event that you feel Burning Shed Ltd has not complied to General Data Protection Regulations you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office which is the Supervisory Authority in the UK. 

This authority upholds information rights in the public interest, promoting openness by public bodies and data privacy for individuals. 

They can be contacted at [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

Your rights - a more technical summary

Here is a summary of the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. 

Your principal rights under data protection law are: 

  1. (a)  the right to access; 

  2. (b)  the right to rectification; 

  3. (c)  the right to erasure; 

  4. (d)  the right to restrict processing; 

  5. (e)  the right to object to processing; 

  6. (f)  the right to data portability; 

  7. (g)  the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and 

  8. (h)  the right to withdraw consent. 

You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can access your personal data by visiting My Account when logged into our website. 

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed. 

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. 

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest. 

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. 

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose. 

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest. 

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is: (a) consent; or 

(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others. 

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement. 

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal. 

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us. This document was created using parts of a template from SEQ Legal ([https://seqlegal.com](https://seqlegal.com/))
